♪Wind♪
♪ الرياح ♪
♪Incidentally blows away fascinating whispers of love♪
♪ يضرب عرضا بيادق الحب الرائعة ♪
♪Whispers of love♪
♪ حراس الحب ♪
♪Sound the best with loyalty to the only valentine♪
♪ دق أفضل بالولاء إلى الوصية الوحيدة ♪
♪The prosperous life♪
♪ الحياة المزدهرة ♪
♪Is when we are together all year round♪
♪ هو عندما نكون معا على مدار السنة ♪
♪For the rest of my life♪
♪ لبقية حياتي ♪
♪All I want is a perfect love with you♪
♪ كل ما أريد هو حبك المثالي ♪
♪I'll remain elegant for you all my life♪
♪ سأبقى أنيقة لك طوال حياتي ♪
♪Giving you my love little by little♪
♪ إعطائك حبي شيئًا فشيئًا ♪
♪I care for you with every piece of my heart♪
♪ أنا أهتم بك في كل قلبي ♪
♪And I miss you every day and night♪
♪ وأنا أشتاق إليك كل ليلة ♪
♪I'll be loyal to you in the best years of my life♪
♪ سأكون مخلصا لك في أفضل سنوات حياتي ♪
♪Melting love with gentle smiles♪
♪ تميّز الحب بالأعمدة الحمقاء ♪
♪I won't be afraid of anything♪
♪ لن أشعر بالخوف من أي شيء ♪
♪And I won't change my heart for you♪
♪ لن أغيّر قلبي من أجلك ♪
=Jade's Fateful Love=
= حب اليشم المؤلم =
=Episode 2=
= الحلقة 2 =
How could you leave me to die?
كيف يمكن أن تتركيني أموت؟
I got you out of the water, didn't I?
أخرجتك من الماء، أليس كذلك؟
You should have given me mouth-to-mouth in the first place.
كان عليك أن تخبرني من الموت
Just now, I...
الآن، أنا...
I thought you were resourceful enough
ظننت أنك ماهرة بما يكفي
to save your own life.
لإنقاذ حياتك
Where are you going?
إلى أين تذهبين؟
To get some food.
للحصول على بعض الطعام
Hey, wait for me.
انتظرني
I didn't expect you to be so good at catching fish.
لم أتوقع منك أن تكوني بارعة جدًا في صيد السمك
And you roast it perfectly.
وتحميصها تمامًا
Looks like
يبدو
it's not that bad to have fallen
ليس من السيئ أن تقع
into the water with you.
أن أسقط في الماء معك
I can enjoy some roast fish.
يمكنني الاستمتاع ببعض السمك المحمص
Are you saying it's bad to fall into the water with me?
هل تقولين إن من المؤسف أن سقط في الماء معي؟
I... I don't mean that.
أنا... لا أقصد ذلك
Then what do you mean?
إذًا ماذا تعني؟
Never mind.
لا عليك
Think about it.
فكر في الأمر
You and I survived together.
نجونا معا
I deserve
أنا أستحق
some of your roast fish...
بعض من سمكك بتحميص
Don't I?
أليس كذلك؟
Ah?
آه؟
Take some yourself.
خذ بعض نفسك
Or do you want me to feed you?
أم أنك تريدني أن أطعمك؟
Oh.
أوه
Maybe I have a look at your jade pendant?
ربما لدي نظرة إلى قلادة اليشم الخاصة بك؟
Your pendant
قلادتك
looks really like mine.
يبدو وكأنني
Indeed.
بالفعل
This is a whole piece.
هذه قطعة كاملة
Oh, they belong together.
إنه ينتمي معا
How did you get this pendant?
كيف حصلت على هذه القلادة؟
My mother gave it to me.
أعطتني أمي إياه
Did she tell you anything about it?
هل أخبرتك أي شيء عن ذلك؟
What about yours?
ماذا عن الخاصة بك؟
I got my pendant
حصلت على قلادي
from a traveling necromancer.
من قرحة العنق المتنقلة
He said
قال
it would get me into some adventures.
سوف يجعلني ذلك في بعض المغامرات
Adventures?
مغامرات؟
So, we survived so many assassinations
لذلك، نجونا من الكثير من الاغتيالات
because of this pendant?
بسبب هذه القلادة؟
I guess so.
أعتقد ذلك
When the jade pendants are combined,
عندما يتم جمع قلادة اليشم
there will be adventures.
سيكون هناك مغامرات
Is it that as long as we stay together,
هل هذا طالما أننا نبقى معا
we won't die?
ألن يموت؟
We don't die now.
نحن لا نموت الآن
But it doesn't mean we won't die.
لكن هذا لا يعني أننا لن نموت
(The necromancer also said,)
(قال العنق أيضا)
(the combination of the pendants will bring peace to this world.)
(جمع القلادة سيجلب السلام إلى هذا العالم)
Chief,
الرئيسة
the Princess of Dongyu has run away.
أميرة دونغيو هربت
We're searching for her separately.
نحن نبحث عنها على حدة
Members of the Dongyu escort were almost dead or injured.
كان أعضاء من ترافق دونغيو شبه مقتولين أو مصابين
(Nan Xun, assassin of the Roufeng Sect) Some remnant guards escaped.
(نان شون، قاتل طائفة روفنغ) هرب بعض الحراس البقية
Within one day,
في غضون يوم واحد
you must find the Princess of Dongyu,
يجب أن تجدي أميرة دونغيو
whether she's alive or dead.
سواء كانت حيّة أو ميتة
If you fail,
إذا فشلت
don't come back to me.
لا تعود إليّ
Aye.
إلى أين
(Wen Yu and I are safe with the pendants.)
(وين يو وأنا في أمان مع القلادة)
(I wonder how Xingyi is doing.)
(أتساءل كيف حال شينغ يي)
(Can his injury get worse?)
(هل يمكن أن تزداد إصابته سوءًا؟)
Still playing?
لا تزال تلعب؟
Wen Yu,
ون يو
you must be thirsty, too.
لا بد أن تكون عطشان أيضا
Here. Have some water.
تفضل، اتناول بعض الماء
The water from the lake
مياه البحيرة
tastes sweet.
طعمها حلو
Sweet, indeed.
حلو بالفعل
Then drink some more.
إذن اشربي المزيد
Then we'll continue our journey.
إذن سنتابع رحلتنا
Why did you dump the leave?
لماذا أمهلت الإجازة؟
You only had one sip?
لم تتناول سوى رشفة واحدة؟
I don't need this kind of water.
لا أحتاج إلى هذا النوع من الماء
What's so bad about it?
ما السيئ في ذلك؟
You just said it tasted sweet.
قلت للتو إن طعمها لذيذ
Hey, wait for me.
مهلًا، انتظرني
Dongyu people like you are supposed to be strong, huh?
من المفترض أن يكون الناس من دونغيو مثلك أقوياء يا هوه؟
Why can't you walk
لماذا لا يمكنك السير
even as fast as the pet we keep?
حتى بالسرعة التي نحتفظ بها؟
Mr. Wen Yu,
السيد ون يو
I'm trying really hard to walk fast.
أنا أحاول حقا المشي بسرعة
Based on your pace,
بناء على الوتيرة الخاصة بك
we won't be able to reach the Capital City
لن نتمكن من الوصول إلى العاصمة
at the time agreed.
في الوقت المتفق عليه
But I can't walk anymore.
لكنني لا أستطيع المشي بعد الآن
I'm good at riding a horse
أنا جيد في ركوب حصان
instead of walking.
بدلا من المشي
How about
ماذا عن
you carry me on your back?
هل تحملني على ظهرك؟
I've never carried anyone before.
لم أحمل أحدًا من قبل
And you're a female.
وأنت أنثى
Actually,
في الحقيقة
you're a nice guy.
أنت رجل لطيف
You're my friend now.
أنت صديقي الآن
There in Beishuo,
هناك في بيشو
I'll be good to you.
سأحسن معاملتك
You're used to your identity quickly.
أنت معتاد على هويتك بسرعة
You talk like a princess now.
تتحدثين كأميرة الآن
Yes, indeed.
أجل، بالفعل
In Beishuo,
في بيشوه
if we still can't find the missing princess,
إذا كنا لا نزال غير قادرين على العثور على الأميرة المفقودة
you'll have to be her.
سيكون عليك أن تكون هي
By then,
إذن
you'll be the real Eldest Princess of Dongyu.
ستكونين الأميرة الأكبر الحقيقية من دونغيو
Hey.
مهلًا
Are you asleep?
هل أنت نائم؟
Chief,
أيها الرئيس
we searched throughout the forest
بحثنا في جميع أنحاء الغابة
but didn't find the missing princess.
لكنها لم تجد الأميرة المفقودة
Maybe she escaped through another route.
ربما هربت عن طريق آخر
We set so many traps,
وضعته في طريق آخر
but they still managed to run away.
لكنهم تمكنوا من الهروب
What on earth went wrong?
ما الخطب يا ترى؟
I failed my job, Chief.
لقد فشلت في عملي أيها الرئيس
I'm ready for the punishment.
أنا مستعدة للعقاب
Who's there?
من هناك؟
Mercy, sir. Mercy.
سيدي، رحمة
I'm just stopping by.
أنا مرتاح فحسب
Where is your princess?
أين أميرتك؟
What princess?
أي أميرة؟
I'll confess.
سأعترف
Tell us.
أخبرينا
Where's the Eldest Princess?
أين الأميرة الأكبر؟
I can take you to her.
يمكنني أن آخذك إليها
But now I'm badly poisoned.
ولكن الآن أنا تحت تسمم بشدة
I guess I'm dying.
أظن أنني أحتضر
I may be dead before we arrive.
قد أموت قبل أن نصل
How about...?
ما رأيك؟
Say it.
قولي هذا
What do you want?
ماذا تريدين؟
How about you detoxify me first?
ما رأيك أن تزيل السموم أولًا؟
Look, I'm so weak now.
انظري، أنا ضعيفة جدًا الآن
I can't make you carry me,
لا يمكنني أن أجعلك تحملك لي
right?
صحيح
Well, you can carry me.
حسنًا، يمكنك حملي
But...
لكن
I may hold you up.
أتمنى أن أحملك
So nagging.
مثير جدًا
Give him the antidote.
أعطه الترياق
Chief,
أيها الرئيس
this is inappropriate.
هذا غير ملائم
How about you be the chief?
ماذا عنك أن تكوني الرئيسة؟
I don't dare.
أنا لا أجرؤ
March him
اآذار / مارس هو
and let him lead the way.
ودعه يقود الطريق
If you dare to fool me,
إذا كنت تجرؤ على خداعي
I'll make your life miserable.
سأجعل حياتك بائسة
Will you ride a horse
هل ستركب حصان
while I run behind you?
بينما أهرب خلفك؟
No.
لا
So, you aren't that cruel.
لذا أنت لست قاسيًا إلى هذه الدرجة
I feel so weak now.
أشعر بالضعف الشديد الآن
I don't think I'm fully detoxified.
لا أظن أنني مُطمئن تمامًا
Tell us where we should go.
أخبرينا إلى أين يجب أن نذهب
If you play a trick again,
إذا خدعت مرة أخرى
I'll dump you.
سوف أقلم لك
You vicious assassin.
أنت القاتل الخبيث
Slow down.
تمهلي
Mercy, madam! Mercy!
رحمة سيدتي! رحمة!
Where should we go?
إلى أين ينبغي أن نذهب؟
To the north. To the south.
إلى الشمال، إلى الجنوب
To... To the north.
إلى الشمال
Where exactly?
أين بالضبط؟
North.
الشمال
Gentleman.
أيها السيد
Thank you.
شكرا لك
Without you,
بدونك
we wouldn't know
لن نعرف
how to get to the Capital City.
كيف نصل إلى العاصمة
We're all from Dongyu.
كلنا من دونغيو
I should help you.
وينبغي أن أساعدك
Gentleman.
أيها السيد
You look happy all the way.
تبدين سعيدة طوال الطريق
What pleases you?
ما الذي يرضيك؟
I'm going to the Capital City to get my daughter back to Dongyu.
سأذهب إلى العاصمة لإعادة ابنتي إلى دونغيو
I can't help feeling happy.
لا يسعني أن أشعر بالسعادة
That's great.
هذا رائع
It's indeed something cheerful.
إنه شيء مبتهج بالفعل
It's so great to go back home.
من الرائع أن عد إلى المنزل
The Capital City
العاصمة
can't be as good as our state.
لا يمكن أن تكون جيدة مثل مقاطعتنا
Yeah.
نعم
Dongyu is better without doubt.
دونغيو أفضل دون شك
The war will be over.
ستكون الحرب قد انتهت
My son was a soldier on the front line.
كان ابني جنديا على خط المواجهة
Now, he's also back home.
الآن، عاد أيضا إلى المنزل
When we raise some cows and sheep,
عندما نجمع بعض الأبقار والأغنام
we'll live a better life.
سنعيش حياة أفضل
If I don't pretend to be the Eldest Princess,
إذا لم أتظاهر بأنني الأميرة الأكبر
what will happen?
ماذا سيحدث؟
The two states will cut ties
المقاطعتين ستقطع العلاقات
or even start a war.
أو حتى بدء حرب
So serious?
بهذه الجدية؟
The marriage of the Eldest Princess
زواج الأميرة الأكبر
represents the sincerity of the states' making peace.
يمثل صدق المقاطعات في صنع السلام
It's about the covenant of the two states.
إنه يتعلق بالعهد بين المقاطعتين
Once it's broken,
بمجرد كسره
the war will be started again.
سوف تبدأ الحرب مرة أخرى
By then, civilians will be homeless.
إذن، سيصبح المدنيون بلا مأوى
The world
العالم
will be plagued by war again.
سوف ابتلي بالحرب مرة أخرى
Let me think about it.
دعني أفكر في ذلك
I don't know where my brother is.
لا أعرف أين أخي
I have no idea how to decide.
لا أعرف كيف أقرر
His Highness's men will escort Xingyi to the Capital City
سوف يرافق رجال سموه شينغ يي إلى العاصمة
and I'll find the antidote for you.
وسأجد العلاج المضاد لك
Are you sure?
هل أنت متأكدة؟
What do I have to do?
ماذا عليّ أن أفعل؟
All you have to do
كل ما عليك فعله
is pretend to be the Eldest Princess.
تتظاهر بأنها الأميرة الأكبر
What are you thinking about?
بماذا تفكرين؟
I think you're right.
أظن أنك محق
I don't think you know where she is.
لا أظن أنك تعرفين أين هي
Be gentle.
بلطف
How dare you fool us?
كيف تجرؤ على خداعنا؟
I'm going to kill you!
سأقتلك!
Sir, I... I...
سيدي، أنا...
Don't bother to waste time.
لا أتكبد عناء إضاعة الوقت
- Don't. - Let's leave.
- لا تفعلي - دعنا نغادر
Here we are.
ها نحن
Why does this man look so familiar?
لماذا يبدو هذا الرجل على دراية كبيرة؟
His Highness sent him to pick us up.
أرسله سموه لإصطحابنا
He's good.
إنه جيد
His Highness is always good.
سموه دائما جيد
- Greetings, Your Grace.
- تحياتي يا غريبك - تحياتي يا غريسك
Xingyi.
شينغ يي
- Xingyi. - Your Highness,
- شينغ يي - صاحب السمو
we lost Mr. Xingyi on the way.
لقد خسرنا السيد شينغ يي في الطريق
Our men are still looking for him.
رجالنا لا يزالون يبحثون عنه
Xingyi.
شينغ يي
Where's my brother?
أين أخي؟
Don't worry, Your Grace.
لا تقلق يا غريسك
Mr. Xingyi is on his way.
السيد شينغ يي في طريقه
Someone will escort him to the Capital City.
سوف يرافقه شخص ما إلى العاصمة
He's so weak.
إنه ضعيف جدًا
How could you leave him alone?
كيف يمكن أن تتركه وشأنه؟
Your Grace, it's a long story.
يا إلهي، إنها قصة طويلة
I'll visit you and apologize another time.
سأزورك وأعتذر في وقت آخر
You had a long trip.
رحلة طويلة
How about you go back and get washed?
ما رأيك أن تعودي وتغسل؟
- Your Grace. - But...
- غريستك - لكن...
The gate is closing soon.
البوابة تغلق قريبا
Get in the carriage.
لندخل العربة
Come, please.
تعالوا، من فضلكم
(The Capital City of Beishuo)
(العاصمة بيشوه)
Delicious and cheap.
لذيذ ورخيص
Sugarcoated haws.
القوس المجفف
This one looks nice.
هذا يبدو جميلا
Toys for sale.
لعب للبيع
Pendants for sale.
الدراج للبيع
How does it taste?
كيف مذاقه؟
Delicious.
لذيذ
Pendants.
الدراج
The Capital City is so gorgeous.
العاصمة رائعة جدًا
Sugarcoated haws.
القديس المجرور
Beishuo
بيشوه
is more prosperous than Dongyu, huh?
أكثر ازدهارا من دونغيو، هو؟
Dongyu is better.
دونغيو أفضل
Sugarcoated haws.
القوس المجفف
Whose carriage is this?
لمن هذه عربة؟
Quite impressive.
مذهل للغاية
It must be a rich family.
يجب أن تكون عائلة غنية
Chief, if we don't take action, it will be too late.
أيها الرئيس، إذا لم نتخذ إجراء، سيكون الوقت قد فات الأوان
Let's get back.
لنعد
The mission failed.
فشلت البعثة
Chief,
الرئيس
I'm sorry.
أنا آسف
I'm just following the order.
أنا أتبع الأمر فحسب
Get started.
ابدأ
(Mild Weather and Bright Scenery) The princess has arrived.
(الطقس الملتوي وتسمع) وصلت الأميرة
- Greetings, Your Grace.
- تحياتي يا غريبك - تحياتي يا غريسك
Now, you're the gentle Eldest Princess of Dongyu.
الآن، أنت أكبر أميرة لطيفة من دونغيو
Remember this.
تذكري هذا
Won't you get in with me?
ألن تدخل معي؟
I'm going for my mission report.
سأذهب لإعداد تقريري عن المهمة
Someone will come out and meet you.
سوف يخرج أحدهم ليقابلك
(I should be gentle and elegant.)
(يجب أن أكون لطيفا وأنيق)
(Now, I'm the Eldest Princess of Dongyu.)
(الآن، أنا أكبر أميرة من دونغيو)
I'm Eunuch Li.
أنا الخصي لي
Greeting, Your Grace.
تحياتي يا غرامك
You're arriving here today
أنت تصل إلى هنا اليوم
and His Majesty cares about you.
وصاحب الجلالة يهتم بك
But restrained by the rule,
لكن مقيدة بالقاعدة
a couple can't meet before the wedding.
لا يمكن لزوجين الاجتماع قبل الزفاف
So, His Majesty gave you a banquet
لذلك، أعطاك جلالة الإمبراطور مأدبة
to show our goodwill for your state
لإظهار نوايانا الحسنة لمقاطعتك
and his care for you.
والاعتناء بك
I appreciate it.
أنا أقدر ذلك
Thank you, Eunuch Li.
شكرا لك، الخصي لي
Oh, Your Grace, you flatter me.
أوه، غريتك، أنت أجمل مني
The Great Consort, the South Prince, and the North Prince
القرينة العظيمة والأمير الجنوبي والأمير الشمالي
also had some imperial dishes sent.
وأيضا بعض الأطباق الإمبراطورية تم إرسالها
I won't stand in your way.
لن أقف في طريقك
I'll take my leave.
سأغادر الآن
Butler, walk him out.
بتلر، أرافقه في الخارج
Yes.
نعم
This way, please.
بهذا الطريق، من فضلك
(Mild Weather and Bright Scenery) Greetings, Your Grace. I'm Qiuju.
(الطقس الشتوي وتسمع اليمين) تحياتي يا غريبك أنا تشي وجو
The Great Consort
القرينة العظيمة
offered shark fin soup,
قدم حساء زعنفة سمك القرش
pork rolls,
لقطات لحم الخنزير
and lotus roots
وجذور اللوتس
to welcome you, Your Grace.
للترحيب بك يا غرفتك
Greetings, Your Grace. I'm Rubing.
تحياتي يا غريسك أنا أصطحب إلى الجنوب
The North Prince
الأمير الشمالي
offered fried sparrows,
قدم شرارات مقلي
seafood balls,
كرات الأغذية البحرية
and Maojian Tea
والشاي
to welcome you, Your Grace.
للترحيب بك يا غراسك
Wish you a happy life in Beishuo.
أتمنى لك حياة سعيدة في بيشوه
Greetings, Your Grace. I'm Lizi.
تحياتي يا غريسك أنا ليزي
Knowing about your arrival, the South Prince
معلومات عن وصولك، الأمير الجنوبي
had me deliver the most precious dishes.
طلب مني تسليم أثمن الأطباق
Steamed bear's paws,
أحذية الدجاج على البخار
diced chicken meat with fleece-flower Root,
لحم الدجاج المعالج مع سجادة الزهور
and sweet duck tongues.
ولغة البطة الحلوة
Wish you good luck, longevity, and health.
أتمنى لك حظًا موفقًا وطول العمر والصحة
Greetings, Brother.
تحياتي يا أخي
You may rise, Shiyu.
انهض، شيو
(Zhou Chenyu, the Emperor of Beishuo)
(تشو تشينو، إمبراطور بيشوه)
Shiyu,
شييو
I heard you had a very dangerous trip.
سمعت أن لديك رحلة خطيرة جدا
As your eldest brother,
كأخوك الأكبر لك
I should have protected you.
كان يجب أن أحميك
But this time,
ولكن هذه المرة
you had to risk your life to Dongyu
كان عليك أن تخاطروا بحياتك إلى دونغيو
for the peace negotiation.
بمفاوضات السلام
I really feel sorry.
أشعر بالأسف حقا
Unfortunately, due to my oversight,
لسوء الحظ، بسبب خطئي
the real princess is missing.
الأميرة الحقيقية مفقودة
I feel so sorry, Brother.
أشعر بالأسف يا أخي
It doesn't matter.
لا يهم ذلك
(Letter of Marriage Between Beishuo and Dongyu)
(خطاب زواج بين بيشو ودونغ يو)
As long as this girl
طالما هذه الفتاة
can give us the power of Dongyu
يمكن أن يمنحنا قوة دونغيو
and get us out of Uncle's impedance,
لإخراجنا من عزف العم
whether she's a princess or a maid
سواء كانت أميرة أو خادمة
does not really matter.
لا يهم حقا
You need to arrange more guards
تحتاج إلى ترتيب المزيد من الحراس
to keep the princess safe
للحفاظ على سلامة الأميرة
in case something goes wrong
في حالة حدوث خطأ ما
before the wedding.
قبل الزفاف
I will.
سأفعل
The marriage
الزواج
will end the war between Beishuo and Dongyu,
سوف ينهي الحرب بين بيشو ودونغ يو
stabilize the political situation,
لتحقيق الاستقرار السياسي
and secure the border for years.
وتأمين الحدود لسنوات
I'll carefully protect the princess.
سأحمي الأميرة بعناية
But Brother,
لكن أخي
before Uncle returns from the suppression,
قبل عودة العم من القمع
you should issue the marriage edict soon.
يجب أن تصدر مرسوم الزواج قريبا
In tomorrow's morning court,
في صباح الغد محكمة
I'll announce the marriage thing.
سأعلن أمر الزواج
After the marriage,
بعد الزواج
hope the two states can always be peaceful.
آمل أن تتمكن المقاطعتان من أن تكونا مسالمين دائما
It's also what I wish for.
هذا ما أتمنى أيضًا
She's such a vicious assassin.
يا لها من قاتل شريرة
What is the point
ما الهدف
of having a pretty face?
أن يكون لها وجه جميل؟
She kills people, anyway.
إنها تقتل الناس على أي حال
Oh, this.
هذا
I can use it.
يمكنني استخدامها
She discarded me mercilessly.
لقد تخليت عني بلا رحمة
So ruthless.
لا ترحم
When I recover...
عندما أتعافى...
When I recover,
عندما أشعر بالتعافي
I'll show her
سأظهر لها
how strong I can be.
كم أنا قوية
Just you wait,
فقط أنت تنتظر
vicious assassin.
قاتل شريرة
(Mild Weather and Bright Scenery)
(الطقس البارد والمشهور)
Is this the way
هل هذه هي الطريقة
the Eldest Princess usually eats?
أبرز أميرة عادة ما تأكل؟
Wen Yu, you're back.
ون يو، لقد عدت
The food in your state
الطعام في مقاطعتك
tastes really nice.
مذاقها جميل حقا
Is that true?
هل هذا صحيح؟
Yes, of course.
نعم، بالطبع
A lot of people delivered the dishes.
قدم الكثير من الناس الأطباق
Each is more exquisite than the last.
كل واحد منها أكثر تهذيبا من الأخير
And they are said to be
ويقال إنهم كانوا
the imperial dishes.
الأطباق الإمبراطورية
You've never tasted any, huh?
لم تتذاق أبدا، هوه؟
Come on.
هيا
You have some, too. Enjoy it.
لديك بعض أيضًا، استمتعي بذلك
Thanks.
شكرًا
Tastes great.
مذاقها رائع
Why do I feel I'm sleepy?
لماذا أشعر أنني أنام؟
You eat alone.
تتناول الطعام بمفردك
I'll go get some sleep.
سأذهب وأنام قليلًا
Oh, no.
لا
The pastry is poisonous.
المعجنات سامة
My Lord.
سيدي
Wake up, My Lord.
استيقظ يا سيدي
Your Grace.
استيقظ يا غراسك
Wake up, Your Grace!
استيقظ يا غرامك!
What happened, Your Grace?
ماذا حدث يا ملك؟
Fire.
أطلق
Somebody come! Fire!
تعال شخص! أطلق!
Hurry.
بسرعة
- Don't move. - Why are you arresting me?
- لا تتحرك - لماذا تقوم باعتقالي؟
Your Grace.
غريسك
You...
أنت...
Seeing I'm not poisoned,
رؤيتي لست مسموما
you must be disappointed, huh?
يجب أن تكونا محبطين، هوه؟
We're back to life again.
عدنا إلى الحياة مرة أخرى
Can the pastry be poisonous?
هل يمكن أن يكون المعجنون سامة؟
Obviously.
من الواضح
Didn't they say
ألم يقولوا
they wanted to make nice to the Princess of Dongyu?
أرادوا أن يعاملوني بلطف أميرة دونغيو؟
Why did they try to kill me?
لماذا حاولوا قتلي؟
Just some claptraps.
الفخاخ المتفجرة فقط
But they looked really sincere.
لكنهم بدوا صادقين حقا
Who exactly poisoned us?
من سممنا بالضبط؟
The Emperor?
الإمبراطور؟
The Great Consort?
القرينة العظيمة؟
The South Prince.
الأمير الجنوبي
The North Prince.
الأمير الشمالي
The guards or the chefs?
الحراس أو الطهاة؟
The eunuch.
الخصي
Everyone is suspicious.
الجميع مشبوهة
You people are vicious.
أنت شريرة بين الناس
If our princess really came,
إذا جاءت أميرتنا حقا
she would be dead many times.
ستكون ميتة عدة مرات
Oh, no.
لا
She couldn't even make it to the Capital City.
لم تصل إلى العاصمة حتى
Mind your tongue.
اهتم لسانك
I can't even complain?
لا يمكنني حتى الشكوى؟
Can I stop
هل يمكنني التوقف
pretending to be the Eldest Princess?
التظاهر بأنك الأميرة الأكبر؟
You can't.
لا يمكنك
It's not time to shrink back.
ليس الوقت المناسب للانكماش
And don't you want to know
ألا تريد أن تعرف
who poisoned you?
من سممك؟
Right.
صحيح
We must catch this bad guy.
يجب أن نقبض على هذا الرجل السيء
The poisoner
المسمم
must be on the same team
يجب أن يكون في نفس الفريق
with the assassins on our way back.
مع القاتل في طريق عودتنا
I guess they'll ambush us tonight.
أعتقد أنهم سيكشفون لنا الليلة
They followed us to the Capital City.
تبعونا إلى العاصمة
This guy must be very powerful.
لا بد أن هذا الرجل قوي جدا
He poisoned the pastry to kill you
سمّم المعجنات لقتلك
even on the first day you settled down.
حتى في اليوم الأول من استوطنت
The one behind this
الشخص الذي يقف وراء هذا
doesn't seem to be intelligent.
لا يبدو ذكيا
It's a poor trick, indeed.
إنها خدعة سيئة بالفعل
Poison in the pastry.
سم في المعكرونة
This guy must be still here.
لا بد أن هذا الرجل لا يزال هنا
In this case,
في هذه الحالة
we can
يمكننا
draw him out.
ارسمه
Confess.
اعترف
Who sent you to kill me?
من أرسلك لقتلي؟
I don't know.
لا أعرف
why the food is poisonous.
لماذا الطعام سام
Are you sure?
هل أنت متأكدة؟
Why did you slander me
لماذا افترضت علي
for poisoning you?
لتسميتك؟
So
لذلك
the Eldest Princess and I caught the wrong poisoner
أنا والأميرة الأكبر القبض على الشخص المسمم
and wrongly accused you?
وأتهمك خطأ؟
I...
أنا...
I didn't know about the poison thing.
لم أكن أعرف عن السم...
Leave her to me.
اتركيها لي
I put some toxins in the ink
وضعت بعض السموم في الحبر
that can corrode your skin.
يمكن أن تؤكل بشرتك
By then,
بحلول ذلك الوقت
your face
وجهك
will be disfigured.
سيتم تشويهه
I don't know anything.
لا أعرف أي شيء
I really don't know anything.
أنا حقًا لا أعرف أي شيء
(Mild Weather and Bright Scenery)
(الطقس الشتوي واليمين المشهور)
Oh, no.
لا
Your face is ruined.
وجهك فسد
You just kill me.
أنت تقتلني فحسب
I won't confess anything!
لن أعترف بأي شيء!
You aren't even scared of disfigurements.
أنت لست خائفة من التشويه حتى
I'll try the second trick, then.
إذن سأجرّب الحيل الثاني
Oh, no. I can't stand it.
لا، لا أطيق الأمر
I'll confess.
سأعترف
Who's behind all this?
من وراء كل هذا؟
The North Prince.
الأمير الشمالي
The North Prince?
الأمير الشمالي؟
Your Grace,
عرشك
the North Prince sent me.
أرسلني أمير الشمال
You can't distinguish the princes, huh?
لا يمكنك تمييز الأمراء، هوه؟
You work for the South Prince.
أنت تعمل لصالح الأمير الجنوبي
No, it's not him.
لا، ليس هو
Mercy, Your Grace. Mercy!
أرجوك، ارحم!
Spare me, Your Grace!
ارحمني يا ملك!
Wait.
انتظر
Show some mercy, Your Grace.
أظهري بعض الرحمة يا غرامك
We should let
يجب أن نترك
the South Prince have his dignity.
الأمير الجنوبي لديه كرامته
I'll have her sent back there.
سأطلب إعادتها إلى هناك
I don't.
أنا لا أفعل
I don't work for the South Prince.
أنا لا أعمل للأمير الجنوبي
Fine.
حسنا
After the whole day,
بعد اليوم كله
I'm quite tired.
أنا متعب جدا
Is the South Prince really as useless
هل الأمير الجنوبي عديم الفائدة حقًا
as he's said to be?
كما يقال؟
Don't humiliate His Highness.
لا تهانة سموه
He's the wisest man in this world.
إنه أكثر الناس حكمة في هذا العالم
You're loyal.
أنت مخلص
Have her sent back.
اذهب لإرسالها
I sent you to take care of the princess.
أرسلتك لرعاية الأميرة
How come you end up like this?
لماذا ينتهي بك الأمر هكذا؟
And you're even sent back.
وأُعدت حتى
Aren't you slapping His...?
ألا تصفع...؟
Oh, sorry.
آسفة
Can't you see Piggy is sleeping?
ألا ترى الأكولة نائمة؟
(Zhou Zhixuan, the South Prince of Beishuo) Don't make me punish you.
(تشو تشيشوان، أمير بيشوه الجنوبي) لا تجعلني أعاقبك
(Yang Xu, the South Prince's butler) Aren't you slapping His Highness in the face?
(يانغ شو، خادم الأمير الجنوبي) ألا تصفع الأمير على الوجه؟
Butler Yang,
بطلر يانغ
I did what His Highness asked me to do.
فعلت ما طلب مني سموه فعله
But they seemed to be alerted.
ولكن يبدو أنهم تم تنبيههم
I nearly poisoned the Princess of Dongyu.
كادت أسمم أميرة دونغيو
Come on, you...
هيا، أنت...
Poison?
السم؟
Who did you try to poison?
من حاولت السم؟
The...
نحن...
The Princess of Dongyu.
أميرة دونغيو
Are you insane?
هل جُننت؟
You want to screw me, huh?
هل تريدين أن تصرخي مني أليس كذلك؟
Or do you think it's so easy for me
أم أنك تعتقد أن الأمر سهل جدا بالنسبة لي
to be the South Prince?
أن أكون الأمير الجنوبي؟
But...
لكن
You ordered me to do that.
أمرتني بأن أفعل ذلك
I did?
حقًا؟
When did I do that?
متى قمت بذلك؟
Yang Xu.
يانغ شو
- Yes, Your Highness. - Did I order her?
- نعم يا صاحب السمو - هل طلبت منها؟
Yes, you did.
نعم، فعلت
- Right? - Did I order her?
- صحيح؟ - هل طلبت منها ذلك؟
- Yeah. Yes. - Right?
- نعم - صحيح؟
- You did. - Yeah, you did.
نعم لقد فعلت
Did I?
حقًا
Come over.
هيا
Come over here.
تعال هنا
Your Highness.
صاحبة السمو
It's so lovely.
هذا جميل جدًا
Don't run, Piggy.
لا تركضي أيتها الأكولة
This is maid Taozi who will be sent to the Princess of Dongyu.
هذه الآنسة تاوزي التي سترسل إلى أميرة دونغيو
Her little brother was badly sick
كان أخيها الصغير مريضا جدا
and couldn't be cured without your award, Your Highness.
ولا يمكن علاجه بدون جائزتك يا صاحب السمو
So, she swore
لذلك، أقسم
to be your slave.
لتكون رحلتك
That's not necessary.
هذا ليس ضروريا
I'm just too kind
أنا لطيفة جدا
to see this misery.
لهذا البؤس
Taozi, huh?
تاوزي، هوه؟
Who gave you this name?
من أعطاك هذا الاسم؟
So tacky.
مبتذل جدًا
Look at them.
انظروا إليها
Chunhua.
تشون هوا
Qiuyue.
تشيو
Xiachan.
شيان شان
Dongxue.
دونغشويه
Piggy.
أكولة
Such romantic names.
هذه الأسماء الرومانسية
Awesome.
رائعة
Your Highness, don't you remember?
ألا تتذكر يا صاحب السمو؟
You named her Taozi.
سمّيتها تاوزي
You favored fruit at that time.
في ذلك الوقت
So maids of that period were named
لذا تم تسمية خادمات تلك الفترة
Taozi, Leezi, Lezi, Lizi...
لتوسي، ليزي...
Go away.
ابتعد
Such terrible names!
هذه الأسماء الفظيعة!
You must have come up with them.
لا بد أنك ابتكرت معها
Tacky.
تسكي
Yeah, I came up with them.
نعم، أنا صعدت معهم
It's always wise of you, Your Highness.
الأمر حكيم منك دائما يا صاحب السمو
Do you know what you're supposed to do there?
هل تعرف ما يُفترض بك أن تفعله هناك؟
According to Butler Yang,
وفقا لبتلر يانغ
I should take care of the Prince of Dongyu
يجب أن أعتني بأمير دونغيو
and get information for you.
والحصول على المعلومات لك
These aren't the most important.
هذه ليست الأكثر أهمية
The most important thing is
أهم شيء هو
the North Prince got her back.
استعدها أمير الشمال
Then she's on his side, right?
إذًا فهي إلى جانبه أليس كذلك
She's the opposite of me, huh?
إنها بعكس أمري، أهو؟
So, I must give her a hard time!
لذلك يجب أن أضايقها!
Yes.
نعم
Darn it, the North Prince.
اللعنة! الأمير الشمالي
He took all the credit.
أخذ كل الفضل
I should have gone there.
كان ينبغي لي الذهاب إلى هناك
Your Highness, I heard the North Prince
سموك، سمعت أن الأمير الشمالي
nearly died on his way back.
كاد أن يموت في طريق عودته
So did the Princess of Dongyu.
وكذلك أميرة دونغيو
Stop running.
توقف عن الركض
Nearly died?
تقريبا ماتت؟
If only Zhou Shiyu died!
إذا مات تشو هو فقط!
Then he wouldn't dare to stand against me.
ثم لن يجرؤ على الوقوف ضدي
Sadly, he's lucky enough to live.
للأسف، إنه محظوظ بما يكفي ليعيش
He's coming to town soon.
إنه سيأتي إلى المدينة قريبًا
Darn it.
اللعنة!
The terrible Princess of Dongyu.
أميرة دونغيو المريعة
I wish they would both die!
أتمنى أن يموتا كلاهما!
I get it, Your Highness.
فهمت يا صاحبة السمو
I won't let you down.
لن أخذلك
Idiot. You piss me off.
غبي، أنت تشفق عليّ
It's all my fault.
كل هذا خطأي
I just tried to help you, Your Highness.
حاولت فقط مساعدتك يا صاحب السمو
Tried to help me?
حاولت مساعدتي؟
Help me?
لمساعدتي؟
Then why didn't you kill her?
إذن لماذا لم تقتلها؟
I nearly...
كدت...
That was close.
كان ذلك قريبًا
She just nearly...
كادت...
Wait, wait.
مهلًا
If you had killed her,
إذا كنت قد قتلتها
I would be screwed, too.
سأكون مفككة أيضا
Look at you.
انظري لنفسك
Oh, that is infuriating.
هذا يثير غضبي
Leave us.
اتركنا
Don't stay to annoy His Highness.
لا تبق لإزعاج سموه
I'll... I'll take my leave.
سوف... سأغادر
Your Highness,
صاحب السمو
the North Prince's men sent Taozi back.
رجلان من الأمير الشمالي أعيدا تاوزي
He had a letter for you, too.
كان لديه رسالة لك أيضًا
(The North Prince's Mansion)
(قصر الأمير الشمالي)
I'll let you go this time.
سأتركك هذه المرة
Hope you'll behave yourself.
آمل أن تتصرف بنفسك
Zhou Shiyu!
تشو شي يو!
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو
- Calm down, Your Highness. - Don't be angry, Your Highness.
- اهدأ يا صاحب السمو - لا تغضب يا صاحب السمو
I ride faster than you.
أقكب أسرع منك
Can you catch up?
هل يمكنك تدارك ما فاتها؟
Your Highness, cool down.
صاحب السمو، رائع
I thought after I survived the assassination
فكرت بعد أن نجت من الاغتيال
and reached Beishuo,
ووصلت إلى بيشو
I could be relieved.
أشعر بالارتياح
But today, I was nearly poisoned.
ولكن اليوم، كنت مسمومة تقريبا
I just don't understand.
أنا فقط لا أفهم
Are Beishuo people
هل شعب بيشو
so eager to kill our Eldest Princess?
حريصة جدا على قتل أكبر أميرتنا؟
The Eldest Princess is powerful
الأميرة الأكبر قوية
and her marriage represents the peace of the world.
وزواجها يمثل السلام في العالم
Those who want peace are supportive.
أولئك الذين يريدون السلام يؤيدون
But still a lot of people want to stir the pot.
ولكن لا يزال الكثير من الناس يريدون تحريك الوعاء
We don't know who is behind the assassination.
لا نعرف من يقف وراء الاغتيال
Now, the South Prince is a trouble, too.
الآن، الأمير الثالث مشكلة أيضًا
It really gives me a headache.
هذا يسبب لي الصداع حقًا
Don't worry about the South Prince.
لا تقلقي حيال أمير الجنوب
He isn't smart enough.
إنه ليس ذكيا بما فيه الكفاية
Indeed.
بالفعل
Just as the rumor goes,
تماما كما تقول الشائعات
there are great talents in your state.
هناك مواهب عظيمة في مقاطعتك
The useless North Prince
الأمير الشمالي عديم الفائدة
and the worthless South Prince.
والأمير الجنوبي الذي لا قيمة له
Rather impressive.
مثير للإعجاب إلى حد ما
You flatter us, Your Grace.
أنت أجمل منا يا ملك
I don't mean that.
أنا لا أعني ذلك
Now, you and I
الآن، أنا وأنت
are both in this together.
كلاهما في هذا معا
And you're a native.
وأنت من الشعوب الأصلية
In the future,
في المستقبل
you'll have to help me.
سيكون عليك أن تساعدني
We both have the pendants
كلانا لديه القلادة
and we'll risk our lives together.
وسنخاطر بحياتنا معا
Besides,
بالإضافة إلى ذلك
I've been taking you as one of us.
كنت آخذك كواحد منا
And you are
وأنت
so righteous, kind, and brave.
نعم ولطيفة وشجاعة
Just tell me.
أخبرني فحسب
What do you want?
ماذا تريد؟
Wen Yu,
ون يو
it's not that I'm scared.
ليس الأمر أنني خائفة
But I have to pretend to be the Eldest Princess.
ولكن يجب أن أتظاهر بأنني الأميرة الأكبر
I can't die.
لا يمكنني أن أموت
So, you might as well
لذلك، من الأفضل لك
stay in the room and protect me.
ابقي في الغرفة وحماية لي
It's good for both you and me.
هذا جيد لي ولك
How... How can I sleep like this?
كيف يمكنني النوم هكذا؟
Umm...
أمي
I'll loosen it.
سآسرها
Then you can sleep on the ground.
إذن يمكنك النوم على الأرض
On the ground?
على الأرض؟
♪Clouds slowly float across the sky♪
♪ الغيوم تطفو ببطء عبر السماء ♪
♪Telling what is awfully bothering♪
♪ وضع ما يزعج كثيرا ♪
♪Ceaseless, love lingers and lingers♪
♪ لا يتوقف، أحب الأمور المتبقية والدائمة ♪
♪You and I both know it♪
♪ أنا وأنت نعرف ذلك ♪
♪In this world, we stay side by side♪
♪ في هذا العالم، نبقى جنبا إلى جنب ♪
♪Watching the stars rise and fall♪
♪ مشاهدة النجوم ترتفع وتنخفض ♪
♪My eyes are red from missing you♪
♪ عيني أحمر من غيابكم ♪
♪Tonight, I hope the moonlight will♪
♪ ليلة، آمل أن يكون ضوء القمر ♪
♪Kiss your eyebrows♪
♪ قبلة حاجباك ♪
♪I'll always be in love with you♪
♪ سأكون دائمًا في حبك ♪
♪Promising it'll last forever♪
♪ مؤشر على أنها ستدوم إلى الأبد ♪
♪As the breeze blows, the flower fades♪
♪ مع ضربات النسيم، تتلاشى الزهرة ♪
♪Leaving a wish to be fulfilled♪
♪ إنقاذ أمنية يتعين تحقيقها ♪
♪To have joy for the rest of its life♪
♪ للفخر لبقية حياتها ♪
♪I'll stay with you for thousands of years♪
♪ سأبقى معك بآلاف السنين ♪
♪Until we grow old together♪
♪ حتى نتقدم في السن معا ♪
♪As the breeze blows, the flower fades♪
♪ كما ضربات النسيم، تتلاشى الزهرة ♪
♪When I look back, you whisper♪
♪ عندما أنظر إلى الوراء، أنت أتذمر ♪
♪Then I wake up from the dream♪
♪ إذن أستيقظ من الحلم ♪
♪Like how we met for the first time♪
♪ مثل كيفية التقينا للمرة الأولى ♪